# Oluwaloseyi Marvellous Adeleye

# **Backend Software Developer**

Lagos, Nigeria +2349046329231

seyiadel03@gmail.com

Github: www.github.com/seyiadel

# **SUMMARY**

A Junior Backend Software Developer with over a year experience in developing software solutions through internships and personal projects. A curious mind ready to learn and explore backend engineering to build, scale, identify and provide solutions for bugs.

# **SKILLS**

Languages: Go, Python

Frameworks: Gin, Django, FastAPI

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Version Control: Git
Containers: Docker
EXPERIENCE

Hotels.NG Internship, Lagos - Junior Backend Software Engineer

OCTOBER 2022 - DECEMBER 2022

- Working with professionals in the tech space ranging from Product Managers, Product Designers, Frontend Engineers and Backend Engineers to develop an Artificial Intelligence backed Web Application that generates, schedules letters and sends to loved ones with a subscription plan.
- Designing the sequence diagram on how requests and responses should flow to increase faster query runtime from the Artificial Intelligence to the User's request and Subscription Plan.
- Wrote the transaction and image upload endpoints as a major while fixing bugs from other ticketed endpoints using FastAPI.

#### 14G Zuri Internship, Lagos - Backend Engineer

APRIL 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2022

- Contributing to a price compare web application with django to ease users and increase productivity by 30%. Provide product information through a search and you get the result based on your preferred requirements.
- Wrote the web scraper REST endpoint using Beautiful Soup as the required library to scrape information from e-commerce sites in Nigeria and Kenya into a CSV format to compare prices.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Plan Subscription API

Repository: https://github.com/seyiadel/Plan-Subscription-API

- User Authentication and Authorization was implemented as Token Authentication using a third party library called django-rest-knox
- Payment Process and Verification was implemented consuming Paystack (Stripe) Payment Infrastructure API

#### One Time Password Generator and Validator with Go

Codebase Repository: https://github.com/seyiadel/otp-go

A package written in Go to authorize and validate one time passwords being generated by the package for email based accounts. This package is written following a banking application's forgotten password workflow. Using Gorm as the Object Relational mapper and MySQL as Database.

# TautPAD- A REST API in Go

Codebase Repository: https://github.com/seyiadel/Taut-Pad-API

A Note Taking API using Go Internal Libraries and MongoDB as the database. This project was done to understand how REST API works in Golang. I learnt there is more that can be done using Gorilla Mux, Object Relational Mapper like Gorm and Web Frameworks like Gin. Implementing structs, the use of interfaces and context works.

# **EDUCATION**

**Yaba College Of Technology, Yaba, Lagos** - National Diploma in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

SEPTEMBER 2018 - NOVEMBER 2021

**Olabisi Onabanjo University, Ago-lwoye -** Bachelors in Computer Engineering [PRESENT]